Guide to the Pare Lorentz papers,
Rare Book and Manuscript Library Columbia University Libraries
- Series VI: Office Files, 1935-1979, undated
  - Subseries 5. General Files, 1930s-1948
    - DeBrie, Andre, Inc., 1937-1940 (Box 98, Folder 11)
    - Bell and Howell Company, 1937-1940 (Box 98, Folder 12)
    - American Recono, Inc., 1937-1940 (Box 98, Folder 13)
    - U.S. Despatch Agency, 1937-1940 (Box 98, Folder 14)
    - Tri-States Theatre Corp., 1937-1940 (Box 98, Folder 15)
    - Ruby Camera Company, 1937-1940 (Box 98, Folder 16)
    - Romeike Clipping Service, 1937-1940 (Box 98, Folder 17)
    - Railway Express, 1937-1940 (Box 98, Folder 18)
    - Pavelle Laboratories, 1937-1940 (Box 98, Folder 19)
    - Paramount News, 1937-1940 (Box 98, Folder 20)
    - Paramount Pictures Corp., 1937-1940 (Box 98, Folder 21)
    - Paramount Productions Inc., 1937-1940 (Box 98, Folder 22)
    - New York Telephone, 1937-1940 (Box 98, Folder 23)
    - Movietone News, 1937-1940 (Box 98, Folder 24)
    - Motion Picture Camera Supply Company, 1937-1940 (Box 98, Folder 25)
    - International Cinema, Inc., 1937-1940 (Box 98, Folder 26)
    - H.E.R. Laboratory, 1937-1940 (Box 98, Folder 27)
    - General Service, 1937-1940 (Box 98, Folder 28)
    - Emerson Electric, 1937-1940 (Box 98, Folder 29)
    - Eastern Service Studios, Inc., 1937-1940 (Box 98, Folder 30)
    - A.B. Dick Co., 1937-1940 (Box 98, Folder 31)
    - Music Publishers Protective Association, 1937-1940 (Box 98, Folder 32)
    - De Luxe Fire, 1937-1940 (Box 98, Folder 33)
    - DeLuxe Laboratories, 1937-1940 (Box 98, Folder 34)
    - De Luxe Orders, 1937-1940 (Box 99, Folder 1)
    - Boston Water Purifier, 1937-1940 (Box 99, Folder 2)
    - Akeley-Leventhal "Editor", 1937-1940 (Box 99, Folder 3)
    - Service Certificates, 1937-1940 (Box 99, Folder 4)
    - Personnel, 1937-1940 (Box 99, Folder 5)
    - Requisitions and Purchase Orders, 1937-1940 (Box 99, Folder 6)
    - Travel and Salary, 1937-1940 (Box 99, Folder 7)
    - Bill of Ladings, 1937-1940 (Box 99, Folder 8)
    - Current Bills--Production #3, 1937-1940 (Box 99, Folder 9)
    - Academy of Motion Picture Arts, 1938-1939 (Box 99, Folder 10)
    - AGFA ANSCO Corp., 1938-1939 (Box 99, Folder 11)
    - Air Travel, 1938-1939 (Box 99, Folder 12)
    - American Map Co., 1938-1939 (Box 99, Folder 13)
    - Angelica Jacket Co., 1938-1939 (Box 99, Folder 14)
    - Appropriations, 1938-1939 (Box 99, Folder 15)
    - Arrow Photo Service, 1938-1939 (Box 99, Folder 16)
    - Art Metal Construction, 1938-1939 (Box 99, Folder 17)
    - Automobiles--General, 1938-1939 (Box 99, Folder 18)
    - Bass Camera Co., 1938-1939 (Box 99, Folder 19)
    - Bell and Howell--Chicago, 1938-1939 (Box 99, Folder 20)
    - Bell and Howell--New York, 1938-1939 (Box 99, Folder 21)
    - Bell and Howell--Los Angeles, 1938-1939 (Box 99, Folder 22)
    - Bigelow Carpet Co., 1938-1939 (Box 99, Folder 23)
    - Boston Water Purifier, 1938-1939 (Box 99, Folder 24)
    - Brand, Paul, 1938-1939 (Box 99, Folder 25)
    - Breakdown March 31, 1938-1939 (Box 99, Folder 26)
    - Brentano’s Book Stores, 1938-1939 (Box 100, Folder 1)
    - Bridgeman, 1938-1939 (Box 100, Folder 2)
    - Bruno--New York, 1938-1939 (Box 100, Folder 3)
    - Budgets--Monthly, 1938-1939, (6 Folders) (Box 100, Folder 4 to 9)
    - Burk’s Service--Cleveland, 1938-1939 (Box 100, Folder 10)
    - Burroughs Welcome, 1938-1939 (Box 100, Folder 11)
    - Camera Equipment Co., 1938-1939 (Box 100, Folder 12)
    - Campbell, W.D., 1938-1939 (Box 100, Folder 13)
    - Capper and Capper Ltd., 1938-1939 (Box 100, Folder 14)
    - Chicago Film Labs, 1938-1939 (Box 100, Folder 15)
    - Carey Cadillac Co., 1938-1939 (Box 100, Folder 16)
    - Central Garage, 1938-1939 (Box 100, Folder 17)
    - Chicago Maternity, 1938-1939 (Box 100, Folder 18)
    - Civil Service, 1938-1939 (Box 100, Folder 19)
    - Columbia Broadcasting, 1938-1939 (Box 100, Folder 20)
    - Commercial Radio Sound, 1938-1939 (Box 100, Folder 21)
    - Contracts, 1938-1939, (6 Folders) (Box 100, Folder 22 to 27)
    - Crown Curtain Company, 1938-1939 (Box 100, Folder 28)
    - Desks Inc., 1938-1939 (Box 100, Folder 29)
    - De Luxe Labs, 1938-1939, (2 Folders) (Box 101, Folder 1 to 2)
    - A.B. Dick, 1938-1939 (Box 101, Folder 3)
    - Eastern Service Studios, 1938-1939 (Box 101, Folder 4)
    - Eastman Kodak, 1938-1939, (3 Folders) (Box 101, Folder 5 to 7)
    - Elec. App. and Sales, 1938-1939 (Box 101, Folder 8)
    - Equitable Stationery Company, 1938-1939 (Box 101, Folder 9)
    - ERB Electrical, 1938-1939 (Box 101, Folder 10)
    - FSA Still Lab, 1938-1939 (Box 101, Folder 11)
    - Federal Offices--NY, 1938-1939 (Box 101, Folder 12)
    - Foreign Distribution, 1938-1939 (Box 101, Folder 13)
    - Sidney Friedman, 1938-1939 (Box 101, Folder 14)
    - Fyfe, Howard, 1938-1939 (Box 101, Folder 15)
    - GAO Decisions, 1938-1939 (Box 101, Folder 16)
    - General Electric, 1938-1939, (2 Folders) (Box 101, Folder 17 to 18)
    - General Felt Prod., 1938-1939 (Box 101, Folder 19)
    - General Fireproofing, 1938-1939 (Box 101, Folder 20)
    - General Tire and Rubber, 1938-1939 (Box 101, Folder 21)
    - Gilbert Photo Service, 1938-1939 (Box 101, Folder 22)
    - Globe Wernicke, 1938-1939 (Box 101, Folder 23)
    - B.Goodrich, 1938-1939 (Box 101, Folder 24)
    - Gotham Book Mart, 1938-1939 (Box 101, Folder 25)
    - Grand Circus Garage Detroit, 1938-1939 (Box 101, Folder 26)
    - Harris, Leo, Inc., 1938-1939 (Box 102, Folder 1)
    - Haynes Griffin, 1938-1939 (Box 102, Folder 2)
    - Hertz Drivurself Stations, 1938-1939 (Box 102, Folder 3)
    - Huey Co., 1938-1939 (Box 102, Folder 4)
    - International Harvester, 1938-1939 (Box 102, Folder 5)
    - Kelly-Springfield, 1938-1939 (Box 102, Folder 6)
    - Lenauer International Film, 1938-1939 (Box 102, Folder 7)
    - Licensing Agreement, 1938-1939 (Box 102, Folder 8)
    - Lighting Company, 1938-1939 (Box 102, Folder 9)
    - Lloyd’s Film Storage, 1938-1939 (Box 102, Folder 10)
    - Loop Shoppers Garage, 1938-1939 (Box 102, Folder 11)
    - Luce’s Press Clippings, 1938-1939 (Box 102, Folder 12)
    - McInerney, W.A., 1938-1939 (Box 102, Folder 13)
    - MacIntosh and Sheridan, 1938-1939 (Box 102, Folder 14)
    - March of Time, 1938-1939 (Box 102, Folder 15)
    - Marshall Field, 1938-1939 (Box 102, Folder 16)
    - Midtown Chevrolet, 1938-1939 (Box 102, Folder 17)
    - Mitchell Camera Corp., 1938-1939 (Box 102, Folder 18)
    - Moviola Company, 1938-1939 (Box 102, Folder 19)
    - Motion Picture Camera Supply, 1938-1939 (Box 102, Folder 20)
    - National Emergency Council, 1938-1939 (Box 102, Folder 21)
    - National Theatre Supply, 1938-1939 (Box 102, Folder 22)
    - National Van Lines, 1938-1939 (Box 102, Folder 23)
    - NEC--1080s 1938-1939 (Box 102, Folder 24)
    - Negative Reports, 1938-1939 (Box 102, Folder 25)
    - Neumade Products, 1938-1939 (Box 102, Folder 26)
    - New Loop End Garage Chicago, 1938-1939 (Box 102, Folder 27)
    - New York Telephone Co., 1938-1939 (Box 102, Folder 28)
    - New York Post Office, 1938-1939 (Box 102, Folder 29)
    - Office Equipment, 1938-1939 (Box 102, Folder 30)
    - Office Supplies, 1938-1939 (Box 102, Folder 31)
    - Paramount Pictures, 1938-1939 (Box 102, Folder 32)
    - Peerless Towel Supply, 1938-1939 (Box 102, Folder 33)
    - Phillips Petrol, 1938-1939 (Box 102, Folder 34)
    - Postal Telegraph, 1938-1939 (Box 102, Folder 35)
    - Preview Theatre, 1938-1939 (Box 102, Folder 36)
    - Precision Film Labs, 1938-1939 (Box 102, Folder 37)
    - Print Records, 1938-1939 (Box 102, Folder 38)
    - Rabsons Music and Camera, 1938-1939 (Box 103, Folder 1)
    - RCA Mfg. Company, 1938-1939 (Box 103, Folder 2)
    - RCA Communications, 1938-1939 (Box 103, Folder 3)
    - Rainbow Auto Painting, 1938-1939 (Box 103, Folder 4)
    - Rand McNally, 1938-1939 (Box 103, Folder 5)
    - Red Star Garage, 1938-1939 (Box 103, Folder 6)
    - Remington Rand, 1938-1939 (Box 103, Folder 7)
    - Rhoades, Chas. P., 1938-1939 (Box 103, Folder 8)
    - Romeike Clipping Bureau, 1938-1939 (Box 103, Folder 9)
    - Royal Typewriter Co., 1938-1939 (Box 103, Folder 10)
    - Ross Chas, Inc., 1938-1939 (Box 103, Folder 11)
    - Rural Electrification Administration, 1938-1939 (Box 103, Folder 12)
    - Sale of Footage, 1938-1939 (Box 103, Folder 13)
    - Santa Fe, 1938-1939 (Box 103, Folder 14)
    - Security Steel Equipment, 1938-1939 (Box 103, Folder 15)
    - Shell Oil, 1938-1939 (Box 103, Folder 16)
    - Siebel Co., 1938-1939 (Box 103, Folder 17)
    - Smith, L.C. and Corona, 1938-1939 (Box 103, Folder 18)
    - Schirmer, G., 1938-1939 (Box 103, Folder 19)
    - Schmidt, Alfred, 1938-1939 (Box 103, Folder 20)
    - Screen Actors Guild, 1938-1939 (Box 103, Folder 21)
    - Socony-Vacuum, 1938-1939 (Box 103, Folder 22)
    - Standard Forms, 1938-1939 (Box 103, Folder 23)
    - Standard Oil, 1938-1939 (Box 103, Folder 24)
    - Studio Lighting Co., 1938-1939 (Box 103, Folder 25)
    - Stott, Chas. G., 1938-1939 (Box 103, Folder 26)
    - Soil Conservation Camera Truck, 1938-1939 (Box 103, Folder 27)
    - Stromberg Electric, 1938-1939 (Box 103, Folder 28)
    - South America, 1938-1939 (Box 103, Folder 29)
    - Sloane, W. and J., 1938-1939 (Box 103, Folder 30)
    - Farm Security Service Certificates, 1937-1938 (Box 103, Folder 31)
    - 347 Madison Avenue, 1938-1939 (Box 103, Folder 32)
    - Travel Advance, 1938-1939 (Box 103, Folder 33)
    - United Cinephone Corp., 1938-1939 (Box 103, Folder 34)
    - Universal Recording Co., 1938-1939 (Box 103, Folder 35)
    - Underwood Elliott Fisher Co., 1938-1939 (Box 103, Folder 36)
    - United Artists--Sound, 1938-1939 (Box 103, Folder 37)
    - Wabash Photo Lamp, 1938-1939 (Box 103, Folder 38)
    - Western Union, 1938-1939 (Box 103, Folder 39)
    - Wilding Pictures, 1938-1939 (Box 103, Folder 40)
    - WPA, 1938-1939 (Box 103, Folder 41)
    - Clippings--Reviews by Pare Lorentz, 1930s (Box 104, Folder 1)
    - Clippings--Creation of U.S. Film Service, 1938-1942 (Box 104, Folder 2)
    - Clippings--Personal, 1940s, (2 Folders) (Box 104, Folder 3 to 4)
    - Press Releases--Lorentz On Film, 1961 (Box 104, Folder 5)
    - Brentano’s Book Stores, 1939-1940 (Box 104, Folder 6)
    - Bills of Lading, 1939-1940, (2 Folders) (Box 104, Folder 7 to 8)
    - Boston Water Purifier, 1939-1940 (Box 104, Folder 9)
    - Brand, Paul L., 1939-1940 (Box 104, Folder 10)
    - Budgets, 1939-1940, (2 Folders) (Box 104, Folder 11 to 12)
    - Camera Equipment Co., 1939-1940 (Box 104, Folder 13)
    - De Luxe Laboratories, 1939-1940, (4 Folders) (Box 105, Folder 1 to 4)
    - A.B. Dick, 1939-1940 (Box 105, Folder 5)
    - Railway Express Co., 1939-1940 (Box 105, Folder 6)
    - Eastern Service Studios, 1939-1940 (Box 105, Folder 7)
    - Eastman Kodak, 1939-1940, (3 Folders) (Box 105, Folder 8 to 10)
    - Equitable Stationery Co., 1939-1940 (Box 105, Folder 11)
    - Fox, Harry, 1939-1940 (Box 105, Folder 12)
    - Globe Wernicke, 1939-1940 (Box 106, Folder 1)
    - Goldwyn, 1939-1940, (5 Folders) (Box 106, Folder 2 to 6)
    - Gulf Oil, 1939-1940 (Box 106, Folder 7)
    - Harris, Leo. Inc., 1939-1940 (Box 106, Folder 8)
    - Hawley Motor Company, 1939-1940 (Box 106, Folder 9)
    - Hertz, 1939-1940 (Box 106, Folder 10)
    - Kahn, Stephen, 1939-1940 (Box 106, Folder 11)
    - Kass Realty, 1939-1940 (Box 106, Folder 12)
    - Kelly Springfield, 1939-1940 (Box 106, Folder 13)
    - Lightning Co., 1939-1940 (Box 106, Folder 14)
    - Loop Shoppers, 1939-1940 (Box 106, Folder 15)
    - Lloyd’s Film Storage, 1939-1940 (Box 106, Folder 16)
    - Luce’s Press Clipping Service, 1939-1940 (Box 106, Folder 17)
    - Midtown Chevrolet, 1939-1940 (Box 106, Folder 18)
    - MoMA Film Library, 1939-1940 (Box 106, Folder 19)
    - National Cine Labs, 1939-1940 (Box 106, Folder 20)
    - NBC, 1939-1940 (Box 106, Folder 21)
    - New York Post Office, 1939-1940 (Box 106, Folder 22)
    - New York Telephone Co., 1939-1940 (Box 106, Folder 23)
    - Peerless Towel Supply, 1939-1940 (Box 106, Folder 24)
    - Procurement Division, 1939-1940 (Box 106, Folder 25)
    - Postal Telegraph, 1939-1940 (Box 106, Folder 26)
    - Requisitions, 1939-1940 (Box 107, Folder 1)
    - Red Star Garage, 1939-1940 (Box 107, Folder 2)
    - RCA Communications, 1939-1940 (Box 107, Folder 3)
    - RKO Radio Pictures, 1939-1940 (Box 107, Folder 4)
    - Sackett and Wilhelms, 1939-1940 (Box 107, Folder 5)
    - Sale of Footage, 1939-1940 (Box 107, Folder 6)
    - Sante Fe, 1939-1940 (Box 107, Folder 7)
    - Scales, Merwyn, 1939-1940 (Box 107, Folder 8)
    - Society of Motion Picture Engineers, 1939-1940 (Box 107, Folder 9)
    - Socony Vacuum, 1939-1940 (Box 107, Folder 10)
    - Standard Forms, 1939-1940 (Box 107, Folder 11)
    - Standard Oil--California, 1939-1940 (Box 107, Folder 12)
    - Standard Oil--Ohio, 1939-1940 (Box 107, Folder 13)
    - Strong, Edwin Inc., 1939-1940 (Box 107, Folder 14)
    - Surplus Property, 1939-1940 (Box 107, Folder 15)
    - 347 Madison Avenue, 1939-1940 (Box 107, Folder 16)
    - Union Oil of California, 1939-1940 (Box 107, Folder 17)
    - United Artists--Sound, 1939-1940 (Box 107, Folder 18)
    - United Cinephone, 1939-1940 (Box 107, Folder 19)
    - Unity Films, 1939-1940, (6 Folders) (Box 107, Folder 20 to 25)
    - Universal Recording Company, 1939-1940 (Box 107, Folder 26)
    - Western Union, 1939-1940 (Box 107, Folder 27)
    - "A", 1937-1947 (Box 108, Folder 1)
    - Air Transport Command, 1945-1946 (Box 108, Folder 2)
    - "B"-"D", 1937-1947, (3 Folders) (Box 108, Folder 3 to 5)
    - De Luxe Labs, 1937-1947 (Box 108, Folder 6)
    - "F", 1937-1947 (Box 108, Folder 7)
    - Forty-Seven, 1947 (Box 108, Folder 8)
    - "G"-"I", 1937-1947, (3 Folders) (Box 108, Folder 9 to 11)
    - Juilliard Script, 1937-1947 (Box 108, Folder 12)
    - "K", 1937-1947 (Box 109, Folder 1)
    - "L", 1937-1947 (Box 109, Folder 2)
    - Lorentz Address to UAW-CIO, 1947 (Box 109, Folder 3)
    - Invitations to Speak, 1937-1947 (Box 109, Folder 4)
    - Business Correspondence, 1947 (Box 109, Folder 5)
    - Correspondence--Alma Lorentz, 1937-1948, (2 Folders) (Box 109, Folder 6 to 7)
    - Divorce Decree, 1943 (Box 109, Folder 8)
    - Personnel, 1937-1947 (Box 109, Folder 9)
    - Travel, 1937-1947, (4 Folders) (Box 109, Folder 10 to 13)
    - "M", 1937-1947 (Box 109, Folder 14)
    - "N", 1937-1947 (Box 110, Folder 1)
    - National Film Cooperative, 1937-1947 (Box 110, Folder 2)
    - New York File, 1937-1947 (Box 110, Folder 3)
    - Nuremburg Trial, 1937-1947 (Box 110, Folder 4)
    - "P", 1937-1947 (Box 110, Folder 5)
    - Pare Lorentz Associates, 1937-1947 (Box 110, Folder 6)
    - Preview Theatre, 1937-1947 (Box 110, Folder 7)
    - "R", 1937-1947 (Box 110, Folder 8)
    - Reprint Requests, 1937-1947 (Box 110, Folder 9)
    - Correspondence--Roberts-Lorentz, 1937-1947 (Box 110, Folder 10)
    - REA, 1937-1947 (Box 110, Folder 11)
    - "S", 1937-1947 (Box 110, Folder 12)
    - "T"-"U", 1937-1947, (2 Folders) (Box 111, Folder 1 to 2)
    - United Nations, 1937-1947 (Box 111, Folder 3)
    - U.S. Film Service, 1940-1941, (2 Folders) (Box 111, Folder 4 to 5)
    - "V"-"Z", 1937-1947, (3 Folders) (Box 111, Folder 6 to 8)
    - REA Personnel and Productions, 1930s, (17 Folders) (Box 111, Folder 9 to 25)
    - AAA-Agricultural Picture #6, 1939 (Box 112, Folder 1)
    - America is a Farm Land Script, 1939 (Box 112, Folder 2)
    - Production Files, 1930s, (10 Folders) (Box 112, Folder 3 to 12)
  - Subseries 6. Pare Lorentz Associates, 1935-1978
    These folders contain expense accounts, ledgers, billing, and other records relating to Lorentz’s personal production company.
    - Pare Lorentz Associates Formation Documents, 1948 (Box 113, Folder 1)
    - Expense Accounts, 1950 (Box 114, Folder 1)
    - Workmen’s Compensation and NY Disability, 1950-1970 (Box 114, Folder 2)
    - NYS Disability Insurance, 1953-1976 (Box 114, Folder 3)
    - Weekly Payroll Record, 1950-1952 (Box 114, Folder 4)
    - Annual Audits, 1949-1977 (Box 114, Folder 5)
    - Financial Records, 1944-1945 (Box 114, Folder 6)
    - Liquidation of Pare Lorentz Associates, 1978 (Box 115, Folder 1)
    - Dissolution Papers, 1948 (Box 115, Folder 2)
    - Operation Trust Co., 1948-1952 (Box 115, Folder 3)
    - Balance Sheets, 1950, (2 Folders) (Box 115, Folder 4 to 5)
    - Ledger, 1948-1978 (Box 116, Folder 1)
    - Corporate Records, 1947 (Box 116, Folder 2)
    - Accounts, 1955-1977 (Box 117, Folder 1)
    - Journal, 1947-1975 (Box 117, Folder 2)
    - Journal, 1976-1977 (Box 117, Folder 3)
    - Bills, 1936-1940, (5 Folders) (Box 118, Folder 1 to 5)
    - Bills, 1940-1946, (11 Folders) (Box 119, Folder 1 to 11)
    - Insurance, 1939-1946 (Box 120, Folder 1)
    - Taxes, 1935-1946, (6 Folders) (Box 120, Folder 2 to 7)
    - Resettlement Administration--Pamphlets and Speeches, 1938 (Box 120, Folder 8)
    - Bridgeman, 1935-1936, (2 Folders) (Box 120, Folder 9 to 10)
  - Subseries 7. Subject Files, 1938-1979
    Correspondence and research on assorted subjects, including an inquiry into the state of the Latin American film industry, as well as correspondence with Hubert Humphrey, Eleanor Roosevelt, and Eugene McCarthy.
    - American Airlines Film, 1948 (Box 121, Folder 1)
    - Air Transport Command, 1950 (Box 121, Folder 2)
    - Anti-Defamation League of B’Nai Brith, 1976 (Box 121, Folder 3)
    - Canadian Correspondence, 1977 (Box 121, Folder 4)
    - "Cable Car Concerto," 1948 (Box 121, Folder 5)
    - China--Rural Reconstruction Commission, 1948-1951 (Box 121, Folder 6)
    - Civil Affairs Division, 1948 (Box 121, Folder 7)
    - China Film--National Archives and Records Service, 1976 (Box 121, Folder 8)
    - Columbia River, 1946-1949 (Box 121, Folder 9)
    - Compton’s Encyclopedia, 1969 (Box 121, Folder 10)
    - Democratic Party Convention Platform, 1960 (Box 121, Folder 11)
    - Documentary Films, 1948 (Box 121, Folder 12)
    - D--Miscellaneous, 1950-1974 (Box 121, Folder 13)
    - F--Miscellaneous, 1949-1973 (Box 121, Folder 14)
    - Faubus--Ward, 1958 (Box 121, Folder 15)
    - Creekmore Fath, 1972 (Box 121, Folder 16)
    - Festival del Popoli, 1962 (Box 121, Folder 17)
    - Fight For Survival, 1957-1962 (Box 121, Folder 18)
    - Film Forum, 1971-1977 (Box 122, Folder 1)
    - "The Forty-Niner," undated (Box 122, Folder 2)
    - Franco-American Audio-Visual Distribution Center, 1948-1949 (Box 122, Folder 3)
    - G--Miscellaneous, 1949-1972 (Box 122, Folder 4)
    - Gamesmanship, 1949-1950 (Box 122, Folder 5)
    - "The Good Neighbor," 1948 (Box 122, Folder 6)
    - Leo Goodman, 1965-1970 (Box 122, Folder 7)
    - Philip Graham, 1949-1953 (Box 122, Folder 8)
    - H--Miscellaneous, 1965-1971 (Box 122, Folder 9)
    - Harvard, 1974 (Box 122, Folder 10)
    - Hubert Humphrey, 1951-1959 (Box 122, Folder 11)
    - Interior Department, 1949 (Box 122, Folder 12)
    - J--Miscellaneous, 1949-1975 (Box 122, Folder 13)
    - Justice Robert Jackson, 1949 (Box 122, Folder 14)
    - K--Miscellaneous, 1954-1978 (Box 122, Folder 15)
    - L--Miscellaneous, 1948-1978 (Box 122, Folder 16)
    - The Land, 1951 (Box 122, Folder 17)
    - Russell Lee, 1965 (Box 122, Folder 18)
    - Libel Suits, 1978-1979 (Box 122, Folder 19)
    - Library of Congress, 1976-1977 (Box 122, Folder 20)
    - Liveright, 1972-1973 (Box 123, Folder 1)
    - Lewis and Clark, 1951 (Box 123, Folder 2)
    - Pare Lorentz--Personal Family, 1955-1970 (Box 123, Folder 3)
    - M--Miscellaneous, 1949-1971 (Box 123, Folder 4)
    - Mc-Mac General Miscellaneous, 1949-1967 (Box 123, Folder 5)
    - Eugene McCarthy, 1968 (Box 123, Folder 6)
    - Minimum Wages, 1962 (Box 123, Folder 7)
    - Missouri River Valley, 1948-1949 (Box 123, Folder 8)
    - Museum of Modern Art, 1948-1977 (Box 123, Folder 9)
    - Name, Age and Occupation, 1942-1977, (2 Folders) (Box 123, Folder 10 to 11)
    - National Air and Space Museum, 1972 (Box 123, Folder 12)
    - National Archives Conference on the Use of Audiovisual Archives, 1972 (Box 123, Folder 13)
    - Lloyd Nosler, 1948-1953 (Box 123, Folder 14)
    - O--Miscellaneous, 1953-1969 (Box 123, Folder 15)
    - P--Miscellaneous, 1949-1977 (Box 123, Folder 16)
    - Pacific Cinematheque, 1977 (Box 123, Folder 17)
    - Promotion of Lorentz Films, 1951-1975 (Box 123, Folder 18)
    - R--Miscellaneous, 1950-1969 (Box 123, Folder 19)
    - RAI, 1977 (Box 123, Folder 20)
    - Report From the World, 1950 (Box 124, Folder 1)
    - "The Rural Co-Op," 1947-1949 (Box 124, Folder 2)
    - S--Miscellaneous, 1948-1970 (Box 124, Folder 3)
    - San Francisco International Film Festival, 1962 (Box 124, Folder 4)
    - Wallace Stegner Correspondence, 1961 (Box 124, Folder 5)
    - State of New York Atomic Authority, 1960 (Box 124, Folder 6)
    - Alden Stevens, 1968 (Box 124, Folder 7)
    - T--Miscellaneous, 1949-1976 (Box 124, Folder 8)
    - Tennessee Valley Authority, 1959 (Box 124, Folder 9)
    - U--Miscellaneous, 1950-1963 (Box 124, Folder 10)
    - UAW--Reuther, 1949-1971 (Box 124, Folder 11)
    - United Nations, 1949-1955 (Box 124, Folder 12)
    - UN--Recommendation for a Comprehensive Motion Picture and TV Production Program, 1953-1955, (2 Folders) (Box 124, Folder 13 to 14)
    - University Film Producers Association, 1962 (Box 124, Folder 15)
    - Florida Lecture, 1977 (Box 124, Folder 16)
    - University of Georgia, 1977 (Box 124, Folder 17)
    - A. Geo. Volck, 1938-1940 (Box 125, Folder 1)
    - W--Miscellaneous, 1948-1972 (Box 125, Folder 2)
    - John Horace Wear, 1953 (Box 125, Folder 3)
    - R. Kenly Webster--Re: KDKA Lawsuit, 1977-1978 (Box 125, Folder 4)
    - West Virginia University, 1969-1977 (Box 125, Folder 5)
    - Woody Guthrie Inquiries, 1975-1976 (Box 125, Folder 6)
    - W.J. Weatherby, 1969-1972 (Box 125, Folder 7)
    - Ben Raeburn, 1955 (Box 125, Folder 8)
    - WGBH Boston, 1955-1961 (Box 125, Folder 9)
    - WGBH Program--Radiation and the Federal Responsibility, 1962 (Box 125, Folder 10)
    - WGBH China, 1965-1966 (Box 125, Folder 11)
    - XYZ--Miscellaneous, 1951-1976 (Box 125, Folder 12)
    - Irving Yergin, 1948-1954 (Box 125, Folder 13)
    - Miscellaneous, 1968-1969 (Box 125, Folder 14)
    - Latin American Film, 1938-1940 (Box 126)
      - Letters to Ambassadors, 1938 (Box 126, Folder 1)
      - American Republics Line, 1939 (Box 126, Folder 2)
      - Thurman Arnold, 1930s (Box 126, Folder 3)
      - Budget, 1940 (Box 126, Folder 4)
      - Cine Columbia, 1939 (Box 126, Folder 5)
      - South America--Clippings, 1938 (Box 126, Folder 6)
      - George Gercke, 1938-1939 (Box 126, Folder 7)
      - Gercke Memo to Lorentz, 1939 (Box 126, Folder 8)
      - Pare Lorentz, 1938-1939 (Box 126, Folder 9)
      - March of Time, 1939 (Box 126, Folder 10)
      - Arch A. Mercey, 1938 (Box 126, Folder 11)
      - Movie Research Report, 1938 (Box 126, Folder 12)
      - Music Research Report, 1938 (Box 126, Folder 13)
      - Pan American Union, 1939 (Box 126, Folder 14)
      - President’s Message, 1939 (Box 126, Folder 15)
      - Recommendations on Movies, 1930s (Box 126, Folder 16)
      - Production Budget Confidential, 1938 (Box 126, Folder 17)
      - Research Notes General, 1939 (Box 126, Folder 18)
      - Arthur Rothstein, 1939 (Box 126, Folder 19)
      - Department of State, 1939 (Box 126, Folder 20)
      - Clarence Stein, 1938-1939 (Box 126, Folder 21)
      - Tomlinson Articles, 1938 (Box 126, Folder 22)
      - Treaty Information, 1938 (Box 126, Folder 23)
      - Visual Education, 1940 (Box 126, Folder 24)
      - Clarence Wagener, 1938 (Box 126, Folder 25)
      - Sumner Welles, 1938-1939 (Box 126, Folder 26)
      - Latin America, 1938 (Box 126, Folder 27)
- Series VII: U.S. Army Air Forces, 1941-1947